<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>colethecoder.github.com</title>
    <link>http://colethecoder.github.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://colethecoder.github.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Cole the Coder's blog</description>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2012 21:36:10 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2012 21:36:10 +0100</lastBuildDate>

    
    <item>
      <title>Real Agile</title>
      <link>http://colethecoder.github.com/2012/03/28/Real+Agile</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>tom@colethecoder.com (Tom Cole)</author>
      <guid>http://colethecoder.github.com/2012/03/28/Real Agile</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every time I've been involved with a company that has decided to move from waterfall-style development to an agile process there is always a point sooner or later that someone says &quot;but that's not real agile&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By proclaiming a divergence from the &quot;real agile&quot; people normally mean that you are missing something out that the Scrum / DSDM etc book prescribes, usually the term is used to make a point, normally a negative one, about the process. But should you really be concerned that you are missing something out and does that preclude you from being &quot;agile&quot;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well firstly it's worth understanding the item(s) that people believe you haven't implemented properly, you could have missed something useful, but if with a clear understanding you choose to omit an element of the methodology then I believe you can still can claim to be agile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With any change in process comes challenges and also opportunities to review the way you build software. Sometimes the actual act of getting everyone to think about processes yields benefits itself if only that people actually start to consider the wider process.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comeback Post</title>
      <link>http://colethecoder.github.com/2012/02/07/Comeback</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>tom@colethecoder.com (Tom Cole)</author>
      <guid>http://colethecoder.github.com/2012/02/07/Comeback</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello World&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
  &lt;pre&gt;
    &lt;code class='javascript'&gt;var someCode;
    if(someCode === 'awesome'){
       alert(&amp;quot;it's Tom's&amp;quot;);
    }&lt;/code&gt;
  &lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I will write as much code as I used to (or how to live in complete denial)</title>
      <link>http://colethecoder.github.com/2010/05/21/I-Will-Write-As-Much-Code-As-I-Used-To</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2010 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>tom@colethecoder.com (Tom Cole)</author>
      <guid>http://colethecoder.github.com/2010/05/21/I-Will-Write-As-Much-Code-As-I-Used-To</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It's something you tell yourself when you agree to go from developer to manager. You convince yourself that this new role is something you can do for a percentage of your time and you will fit in the same amount of development as you did before. You'll work a bit harder, you'll get up a bit earlier, you'll do the odd bit at home. You won't.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the first few weeks you think, &quot;I'll just get over this initial settling in period then I'll get down to some code&quot;. You might get a bit done here and there but you'll keep getting interrupted. The big feature for the big product that you were going to get done easily by the deadline is suddenly looking scarily incomplete. You start to scramble for any bit of quiet time to get it done, sleep becomes a distant memory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sooner or later the phone will be off the hook, Outlook will be closed down, the office door barricaded the light off and you'll power through the remainder of the feature. You'll be elated, you knew you could manage the team and get work done. You emerge from your programming cocoon triumphant, but something's wrong, Jimmy, the junior developer, has been sat fiddling with his pet CMS project for three days because there was no one to tell him what to do next. Sven, your über-programmer, has taken it upon himself to rewrite your business logic in IronPython because the hardware he needed to develop his new feature against hasn't been ordered yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your team has become less productive as a direct result of your productivity. It's hard to take but you need to realise that one of your major responsibilities is to remove obstacles from the path of your team not to churn out code. There will be much less work going out the door with your name on it and you need to adjust to that. Your success is now based on what the team produces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will go through denial, I'm pretty sure every developer turned manager does. You need to deal with this and get on with the task at hand. That's not to say stop coding, you really don't want to be that manager that is so distanced from the code base that they can't make good decisions about it but you are going to have to strike a balance. Coding marathons are going to be a rarity but owning a small feature in each release is a good way to keep in touch without burdening yourself with something that will overtake your other responsibilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There's no magic ratio for this, factors like the state of the development process you have inherited, the level of pragmatism of your team and the complexity of projects that are going on are going to cause you to adjust this ratio. Set it at something achievable though, if anything start on the low side, there's going to be plenty of stuff to do.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flashback</title>
      <link>http://colethecoder.github.com/2010/05/20/Flashback-Number-1</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2010 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>tom@colethecoder.com (Tom Cole)</author>
      <guid>http://colethecoder.github.com/2010/05/20/Flashback-Number-1</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I'd never asked to be the boss, my aspirations had always been along the lines of writing something in the next new technology or to work on project x because it looked interesting. Yet here I was sat in the board room in front of the Managing Director being told 'Cole, you're the boss'. Well maybe not the boss but in charge of the other developers and so this strange journey through the world of software development management began.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My predecessor had decided that management wasn't really for him and moved back to a more hands on role. I'd filled in for him on occasions and had been at the company for a while. I generally got work done quickly, communicated with the project managers coherently and hadn't messed anything up too badly and that was enough for the powers that be. I was now, at the tender age of 25, in charge of our 8 strong development team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was given a brief handover and my own office and then left to my own devices. For a second there was a post-promotion chill and I wondered if I'd done the right thing in accepting but before I could contemplate it any further chaos started to break out. My previously neatly filed inbox began to fill with demands for updates and meeting requests, my phone started ringing and didn't stop for hours and the developers started knocking on my door with questions about what they should be doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hmmm this may be a bigger job than I anticipated.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Post</title>
      <link>http://colethecoder.github.com/2010/05/19/First-Post</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2010 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>tom@colethecoder.com (Tom Cole)</author>
      <guid>http://colethecoder.github.com/2010/05/19/First-Post</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So I'm blogging then.... Only time will tell how often I'll update this or how interesting it'll be. The intention is to try and share some of my experiences in, and ideas on, the world of software development and occasionally in the much maligned domain of healthcare software.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    

  </channel> 
</rss>